Iron Eagle II is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Sidney J. Furie.
Chappy Sinclair is called to gather together a mixed Soviet/U.S.
strike force that will perform a surgical strike on a massively
defended nuclear missile site in the Middle East.
Chappy finds that getting the Soviet and U.S.
Pilots to cooperate is only the most minor of his problems as he discovers
someone in the Pentagon is actively sabotaging his mission.
Charles 'Chappy' Sinclair, played by Louis Gossett Jr..
Capt. Matt Cooper, played by Mark Humphrey.
Gen. Stillmore, played by Stuart Margolin.
Col. Vardovsky, played by Alan Scarfe.
Valeri Zuyeniko, played by Sharon Hacohen.
Sgt. Downs, played by Maury Chaykin.
Iron Eagle II (also titled Iron Eagle II: The Battle Beyond the
Flag) is a 1988 action film directed by Sidney J.
Furie and written by Furie and Kevin Alyn Elders.
A sequel to the 1986 film Iron Eagle, it is the second installment of
the Iron Eagle film series, with Louis Gossett Jr.
reprising his role as Charles "Chappy" Sinclair, alongside newcomers Mark Humphrey,
Stuart Margolin, Maury Chaykin, Alan Scarfe, Colm Feore, and Clark Johnson.
An uncredited Jason Gedrick also returns as ace pilot
Doug Masters in the film's opening scene.
Like its predecessor, Iron Eagle II received negative reviews.
It also did not fare well at the box-office, with earnings of $10,497,324.
Despite this, it was nominated for three Genie Awards (Best Actor in a
Supporting Role, Best Sound Editing, and Best Overall Sound).
The film explores themes of israel, airplane, atomic bomb, cold war, pilot.
The tone is emotional.